# ĐOÀN VĂN SƠN

# React Developer

0347200992

2001.sondv@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in Web Development. I have more 2 years of experience in Modern Front-End Web Development and 1 year of Back-End related technologies as NodeJS and Laravel.

With my knowledge of UI/UX design, I enjoy solving front-end problems and creating the best user experience for users. I also spend time learning new technologies and best practices to become a better engineer

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript & TypeScript, PHP, Python.

#### Libraries/Frameworks:

- ReactJS, NextJS, NodeJS, PHP Laravel
- Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, MaterialUI
- Webpack/Babel, Git, Shopify App Bridge

Database Management Systems: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL

#### Other:

- Experience in setting up CI/CD pipelines, using Docker.
- Hands-on experience with Cloud Computing Platforms: AWS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NTQ Solution - Junior Developer (https://shipbae.com)

09/2022 - Now

**Project:** ShipBae (6 members, 1 front-end, 5 back-end)

• Description: ShipBae is a product of Gori Company, a US-based company. It is a logistics software that helps admins and sales staff easily create orders, create shiments or claims. Additionally Supports synchronization and management of orders from 3rd parties such as shopify, tiktok, walmart, shipstation.

#### Technologies:

- Legacy front-end project: React + Metronic
- Migrate to a new front-end project: React + TypeScript + Bootstrap
- Back-end: PHP Laravel, PostgreSQL

#### Responsibilities:

 Build the source code base, Optimize performance and clean code for the frontend source of the project.

- Mainly responsible, Define the architecture, coding convention and estimating front-end task completion time for front-end project.
- Review Code & Support members of the team to ensure code quality.
- Handles all highly complex frontend tasks such as: subdomain, decentralization, onboarding, asidebar, create order, create shipment, create claims, settings page,..
- Ability to create Reusable Components that can be utilized throughout the Application Form Validations and Handling Dynamic Validations for Form using Yup
- Creating Form Using Formik, Yup
- Perform backend tasks using PHP such as payment processing (PayPal),
   barcode generation, and sending Mailchimp emails and syncs order tiktok

# **NTQ Solution - Fresher Developer**

05/2022 - 9/2022

Project: Pilot ShipBae + BaeWatch (3 members, 1 front-end, 2 back-end)

• **Description:** BaeWatch is a subsystem of ShipBae used on shopify to create additional insurance functions for orders.

# • Technologies:

- Front-end: React + TypeScript + Shopify App Bridge + Bootstrap
- Back-end: PHP Laravel, PostgreSQL

# • Responsibilities:

- Build the source code base, Optimize performance and clean code for the frontend source of the project ShipBae and BaeWatch.
- Perform tasks related to authentication and apexcharts at shipbae.
- Perform connection tasks between ShipBae and BaeWatch. In addition, to tasks related to settings, claims, insurance for BaeWatch application on shopify

# **Tigren Solution - Intern Developer**

03/2022 - 5/2022

**Project:** PWA Demo (4 members, 2 front-end, 2 back-end) (https://demo.tigrenpwa.com)

 Description: PWA Demo is provides FULL Magento core features & DIFFERENT interfaces for desktop & mobile

#### Technologies:

- Front-end: React + TypeScript + Tailwind CSS + GraphQL
- Back-end: PHP Magento

# Responsibilities:

- Study source code and Do extensions such as: realated, up shell, cross shell...
- Custom PWA theme: home page, details page,...

Personal project 6/2024 - 9/2024

**Project:** Schat E2EE (https://schat-e2ee.doanvanson.id.vn)

• **Description:** Schat E2EE is my graduation project. It is a website that allows users to send direct messages, share images, emojis, as well as make video and voice calls. Its most distinctive feature is the end-to-end encryption (E2EE) process for sending and receiving messages.

# • Technologies:

- Front-end: NextJS + Tailwind CSS
- Back-end: NodeJS Express, PostgreSQL, AWS

# Responsibilities:

- Build the entire source code including back-end and front-end
- Research and develop real-time features of the application such as sending messages in text, image, voice, and emoji formats. In addition, it also builds voice calling and video calling functions
- Research and develop encryption features terminal message
- Deploy the system to the website using AWS

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

There are also a number of personal and freelance projects (https://doanvanson.id.vn/project)

Personal project 7/2021 - now

- IT Center (https://itcenter.doanvanson.id.vn): The IT center is a software
  written in React.js, PHP Laravel, and Bootstrap. It has key features such as
  searching for courses, creating posts, creating questions, searching for posts,
  questions,...
- Box Studio (https://box-studio.doanvanson.id.vn): Box Studio is a landing page providing services in marketing, media, & multi-platform digital content. It is written in React.js and Bootstrap.
- Booking Care (https://bookingcare.doanvanson.id.vn): Booking Care is a system that helps patients schedule medical appointments. Additionally, it includes an admin page to assist in managing doctors, hospital rooms, and doctor schedules. It is written in ReactJS and Express NodeJS.

#### **EDUCATION & HONORS**

# Academy of Cryptography Techniques (KMA)

9/2019 - 4/2024

Information Security: 3.0/4.0

imermation decarity, e.e. ii.e	
School scholarship for Semester 2 of the academic year 2021-2022	12/2022
School scholarship for Semester 1 of the academic year 2021-2022	6/2022
School scholarship for Semester 2 of the academic year 2020-2021	12/2021
Encouragement prize for the Hackathon competition at the club level	1/2020